lecreuset.com 2017-06-16

# Privacy Policy | Le Creuset

## SECURITY AND PRIVACY

YOUR USE OF THE LE CREUSET.COM SITES CONSTITUTES YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF OUR TERMS OF USE.

THIS PRIVACY POLICY IS ONLY A SUPPLEMENT TO OUR TERMS OF USE. YOU SHOULD CONSULT THE TERMS OF USE FOR TERMS AND POLICIES OTHER THAN PRIVACY.

### SECURITY

This Privacy and Security Policy (this “Privacy Policy”) explains how Le Creuset and each of its operating subsidiaries and affiliates collects, protects, uses and discloses the Personal Information (defined below) that Le Creuset gathers when you use our website located at [www.LeCreuset.com](http://www.lecreuset.com/) or any other website provided by Le Creuset or one of its operating subsidiaries or processing partners (collectively called “the sites”).

LeCreuset.com and its processing partners have put in place security protocols and technologies to secure the information you provide during your visit to the Sites or when completing your business transaction. However, no information transmitted via the Internet is guaranteed to be 100% secure. Thus, while LeCreuset.com and its processing partners work to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our websites, and you do so at your own risk.

### PRIVACY POLICY

**Personal Information** means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a user ID and password, a first and last name, shipping and billing addresses, e-mail addresses, phone numbers or other contact information that is gathered by Le Creuset as described below. Personal information is not the same as **aggregate information** , which is information presented in summary or statistical form which does not contain data that would permit the identificiation of a specific individual without extraordinary effort.

LeCreuset.com respects your privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of the Personal Information you provide during your visit to the Sites. The intent of this privacy policy is to inform you how the contact information you provide is used, the options you have regarding its use, your entitilement to review and correct that information, and your ability to opt out of its use. This Security and Privacy Policy is applicable only to customers in the United States.

To help improve the privacy policy, please send your comments to [Consumer-Comments@LeCreuset.com](mailto:Consumer-Comments@LeCreuset.com).

### HOW LE CREUSET GATHERS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

When you register an account, you will be asked to provide your name, telephone number and e-mail address. Additionally, some of the websites' registry services, such as My Collection or contests, may ask for your birth date, gender, occupation, personal interests, etc. If you are a registered user your contact information is automatically saved.

LeCreuset.com may send you e-mails or postal mail promoting products or events that, based on your preferences, may be of interest to you, unless you have chosen not to receive them. During registration, you may choose not to receive e-mail solicitations from LeCreuset.com by selecting the "opt out" option.

When you purchase a product, you will be asked at checkout to provide your contact information, including billing and shipping addresses and credit card information. Your credit card information is not saved, nor is it accessible in the LeCreuset.com data center or any of the LeCrueset.com files or records. LeCreuset.com will maintain a record of the products you purchased for yourself or as gifts for others. If you purchase a gift for someone, the recipient's contact information is automatically saved in your Address Book for your reference. It is your option to provide the information requested. However, if you choose not to provide the information we request, you may be unable to purchase products or subscribe to various services on the website.

When you request to be on the LeCreuset.com mailing list (for e-mail or regular mail) you will be asked to provide your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number. You have the option to remove yourself at any time from the LeCreuset.com and Le Creuset corporate mailing lists.Any requests to remove or update your contact information may take up to ten days for an e-mail request and six to eight weeks for a postal mail request.

**Le Creuset’s Use of Cookies and Internet Monitoring Technologies**

Cookies are small text files stored by your browser in your computer when you visit our Sites. We use cookies to improve the Sites and make them easier to use. Cookies permit us to recognize users and avoid repetitive requests for the same information.  Cookies also assist us by identifying the types of browsers and operating systems used most frequently by our customers, and how visitors move through the Sites. All of this information enables us to improve the Sites and tailor them to our customers’ needs and preferences. We use cookies for a variety of purposes intended to make our Sites a better service for you. We reserve the right to use cookies to deliver content specific to your needs and interests. We may also use cookies to track user trends and patterns in order to better understand and improve areas of our sites that our users find valuable.  Most browsers will accept cookies until you change your browser settings to refuse them. At any time, you can disable the use of cookies in your browser and still have access to much of the information on the Sites. However, you may not be able to access your account information or complete transactions on the Site unless you permit the use of cookies. In addition, our servers track various technical details about your visit, such as your computer’s Internet protocol address and the pages that you visited.

We also reserve the right to use outside ad companies to display ads on our sites.  These ads may contain cookies. Cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad companies, and we do not have access to this information.

**Interactive or Social Features of the Le Creuset Sites**

We offer interactive and/or social aspects on the Sites. For example, if you choose to express an opinion in an online forum, post a recipe, respond to user polls, or enter any contests, we may ask you for Personal Information. If you request to sign up for newsletters or other promotional materials, or if you send an inquiry to one of our customer service representatives, we may store a record of your request along with any Personal Information allowing us to respond to your inquiry. 

### HOW LE CREUSET USES PERSONAL INFORMATION

**Le Creuset uses Personal Information to interact with customers and suppliers and to improve its business processes.**

Le Creuset uses Personal Information to fulfill orders placed by customers, to respond to the requests of users of the Sites, and to enrich the usefulness of the Sites. Your contact information will also be used should LeCreuset.com personnel need to contact you via phone, e-mail or postal mail regarding your order. This does not constitute a solicitation. We may also use this data to send you information about products, sales and promotions that may be of interest to you.

**Le Creuset uses Personal Information as part of aggregate reports.**

In addition, Le Creuset may use Personal Information, both on an identifiable and aggregate basis, in various analyses intended to help Le Creuset better understand its customers and suppliers. Le Creuset reserves the right to perform such “data mining” activities at its discretion, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

We may combine Personal Information with other information to create aggregate or summary reports, and we may provide aggregate data to other parties for marketing, advertising and other purposes.

If Le Creuset provides information to other parties in aggregate form, such data will not include any identifiable Personal Information concerning specific customers, suppliers or individuals.

### IS PERSONAL INFORMATION EVER SHARED OR DISCLOSED?

Personal Information is used to complete and support your use of the Sites and the services provided thereon and to comply with any requirements of law. Le Creuset may share Personal Information with third parties only as described below:

**Le Creuset may disclose Personal Information as required by law and for the protection of Le Creuset and others.**

Le Creuset may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Le Creuset or its affiliates or the Sites; (2) protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Le Creuset, our employees and contractors, our users or others; (3) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Le Creuset, its Sites or the public; and (4) enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements. The foregoing includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

**Le Creuset may disclose Personal Information to third parties who help us provide our services.  **

We depend upon third party service providers to provide services to us necessary to run our business. We may transmit your Personal Information to third party service providers who assist us in processing orders and payments, shipping products, sending catalogs, performing surveys, conducting sweepstakes, processing job applications, and sending e-mails and newsletters. We use good faith efforts with these third party service providers to require them to protect the privacy of Personal Information by implementing adequate security measures and by using the Personal Information only as authorized and directed by Le Creuset.   

**Le Creuset may disclose Personal Information as part of a corporate transaction.  **

If Le Creuset should ever merge with, acquire or be acquired by another company, whether by merger, stock transfer, or sale of assets, we may disclose, sell or otherwise transfer control of the Personal Information to a third party as part of such a transaction.

**Personal Information may be disclosed if you participate in one or more interactive or social features that Le Creuset may offer on the Sites.**

Le Creuset allows other users of the Sites to browse comments, recipes, questions or other entries that you have submitted or commented on in one or more forums, message boards, product ratings, feedback portals or other interactive or social aspects that Le Creuset may include on the Sites from time to time. Le Creuset may choose to post this data on other features in the future.

### LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES

Our websites may contain links to websites operated and maintained by other retailers who may sell Le Creuset products. Privacy and security policies and practices on these sites may be different from LeCreuset.com’s privacy and security policies and practices. LeCreuset.com has no control over these sites, and you access such linked sites at your own risk. You should always read a site’s privacy and security policies before disclosing any Personal Information on that site.

### SITE SECURITY POLICIES

LeCreuset.com has put in place various procedural, technical and administrative measures to safeguard and secure the Personal Information you provide.

Payment card information is not retained by or available in the LeCreuset.com data center. To the extent our customers’ Personal Information is maintained by us, it is located on a secured server behind a firewall; it is not directly connected to the Internet. The firewall meets recognized industry standards.

LeCreuset.com was developed to accept orders only from Internet browsers that permit communication through Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, such as the most commonly used browsers like Internet Explorer (IE) versions 7.0 or higher and Firefox versions 3.0 or higher. SSL is a technology that provides security for information being transmitted over the Internet.

### CHOICES FOR MAINTAINING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you do not want to receive e-mail, other than purchase acknowledgements and shipping confirmations, please use the unsubscribe button on the bottom of any e-mail sent to you.

You may also contact LeCreuset.com by calling Consumer Services toll-free at 1-877-418-5547, or by e-mailing us at [Consumer-Services@LeCreuset.com](mailto:Consumer-Services@LeCreuset.com). Please include your name, address and phone number, and state your preference for “no e-mail solicitations,” “no mail solicitations,” “no phone solicitations” or any combination of these. Please allow six to eight weeks for us to fulfill your request.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY PROTECTION

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act that took effect on April 21, 2000 imposes certain requirements on websites directed toward children under age 13 that collect information on those children, or on websites that know they are collecting information on children under 13. LeCreuset.com's current policy is to not collect Personal Information from any person under age 13.

### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84 California residents are entitled to ask LeCreuset.com for a notice describing what categories of personal customer information LeCreuset.com shares with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties’ or corporate affiliates' direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of information shared and will include a list of the third parties and affiliates with which it was shared, along with their names and addresses. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: LeCreuset.com   
Attn: Consumer Services Department  
114 Bob Gifford Blvd.  
Early Branch, SC 29916   

In your request, please specify that you want a copy of "Your Le Creuset of America’s California Privacy Rights Notice." Allow 30 days for a response.

### FRAUD PROTECTION

Unfortunately, some unscrupulous people may purport to represent LeCreuset.com. LeCreuset.com will request your credit card information only when you are in the checkout page of the website, or if you call our Consumer Services team to purchase a product.  
When LeCreuset.com becomes aware that someone or some company is using LeCreuset.com without our authorization, LeCreuset.com will take reasonable steps designed to stop that activity. This may take time, and it may be difficult or even impossible to stop that activity. Thus, you should take precautions to protect yourself.

You should keep your password and other Personal Information in a safe location and not share them with anyone. After you complete your visit, please log off your account and close your browser window; this should prevent someone else from accessing your account. This procedure is especially critical if you are sharing a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place, such as a library.

For more information on how to protect yourself, please visit the Federal Trade Commission's Website at [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/).
